<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nels Numan on</title><link>https://ubiq.online/contributors/nels-numan/</link><description>Recent content in Nels Numan on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:50:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ubiq.online/contributors/nels-numan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Extending the Open Source Social Virtual Reality Ecosystem to the Browser in Ubiq</title><link>https://ubiq.online/publication/extending-to-the-browser/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/publication/extending-to-the-browser/</guid><description>ℹ️ To get the code, clone the samples-browserextended branch and take a look at the Web3D blog post for more detailed instructions. Cite with BibTex @inproceedings{10.1145/3611314.3615903, author = {Friston, Sebastian and Congdon, Ben and Numan, Nels and Brandst\&amp;#34;{a}tter, Klara and Izzouzi, Lisa and Thiel, Felix and Zhang, Jingyi and Giunchi, Daniele and Swapp, David and Steed, Anthony}, title = {Extending the Open Source Social Virtual Reality Ecosystem to the Browser in Ubiq}, year = {2023}, isbn = {9798400703249}, publisher = {Association for Computing Machinery}, address = {New York, NY, USA}, url = {https://doi.</description></item><item><title>Ubiq-Genie</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-genie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-genie/</guid><description>-- The integration of external (open-source) projects with social virtual reality (VR) has the potential to enhance the way we collaborate within virtual environments. For example, recent advances in generative AI provide the ability to synthesize textual, auditory, or visual data, enabling new types of virtual experiences. However, these applications often require a high level of processing power, which is typically not available on untethered mixed-reality devices.
Ubiq-Genie addresses this by building on the open-source Ubiq social VR platform and provides a modular approach to server-assisted social VR applications.</description></item><item><title>Ubiq-Genie: Leveraging External Frameworks for Enhanced Social VR Experiences</title><link>https://ubiq.online/publication/ubiq-genie/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/publication/ubiq-genie/</guid><description>ℹ️ The source code of Ubiq-Genie is available on GitHub and is licensed under the Apache 2.0 License. Cite with BibTex @inproceedings{numanUbiqGenieLeveragingExternal2023, title = {Ubiq-{{Genie}}: {{Leveraging External Frameworks}} for {{Enhanced Social VR Experiences}}}, booktitle = {2023 {{IEEE Conference}} on {{Virtual Reality}} and {{3D User Interfaces Abstracts}} and {{Workshops}} ({{VRW}})}, author = {Numan, Nels and Giunchi, Daniele and Congdon, Benjamin and Steed, Anthony}, year = {2023}, pages = {497--501}, location = {{Shanghai, China}}, doi = {10.</description></item><item><title>Exploring User Behaviour in Asymmetric Collaborative Mixed Reality</title><link>https://ubiq.online/publication/exploring-user-behaviour/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/publication/exploring-user-behaviour/</guid><description> Cite with BibTex @inproceedings{10.1145/3562939.3565630, author = {Numan, Nels and Steed, Anthony}, title = {Exploring User Behaviour in Asymmetric Collaborative Mixed Reality}, year = {2022}, isbn = {9781450398893}, publisher = {Association for Computing Machinery}, address = {New York, NY, USA}, url = {https://doi.org/10.1145/3562939.3565630}, doi = {10.1145/3562939.3565630}, booktitle = {Proceedings of the 28th ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and Technology}, articleno = {6}, numpages = {11}, keywords = {mixed reality, augmented reality, collaboration, virtual reality}, location = {Tsukuba, Japan}, series = {VRST &amp;#39;22} }</description></item><item><title>Ubiq-Exp: a Toolkit to Build and Run Remote and Distributed Mixed Reality Experiments</title><link>https://ubiq.online/publication/ubiq-exp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/publication/ubiq-exp/</guid><description>ℹ️ Source code for Ubiq-Exp will be posted to this page soon! Cite with BibTex @article{10.3389/frvir.2022.912078, title={Ubiq-Exp: A Toolkit to Build and Run Remote and Distributed Mixed Reality Experiments}, author={Steed, Anthony and Izzouzi, Lisa and Brandst{\&amp;#34;a}tter, Klara and Friston, Sebastian and Congdon, Benjamin James and Olkkonen, Otto and Giunchi, Daniele and Numan, Nels and Swapp, David}, journal={Frontiers in Virtual Reality}, pages={131}, publisher={Frontiers} }</description></item><item><title>Ubiq Tutorial at ISMAR 2022</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ismar-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ismar-2022/</guid><description>Abstract One of the most promising applications of consumer virtual reality technology is its use for remote collaboration. A very wide variety of social virtual reality (SVR) applications are now available; from competitive games amongst small numbers of players; through to conference-like setups supporting dozens of visitors. Indeed many participants at ISMAR 2022 will be experiencing at least some of the conference through a SVR application. The implementations strategies of different SVR applications are very diverse, with few standards or conventions to follow.</description></item><item><title>Ubiq Tutorial at IEEE VR 2022</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2022/</guid><description>Abstract One of the most promising applications of consumer virtual reality technology is its use for remote collaboration. A very wide variety of social virtual reality (SVR) applications are now available; from competitive games amongst small numbers of players; through to conference-like setups supporting dozens of visitors. Indeed many participants at IEEE Virtual Reality 2022 will be experiencing at least some of the conference through a SVR application. The implementations strategies of different SVR applications are very diverse, with few standards or conventions to follow.</description></item></channel></rss>