<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Klara Brandstätter on</title><link>https://ubiq.online/contributors/klara-brandst%C3%A4tter/</link><description>Recent content in Klara Brandstätter on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:50:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ubiq.online/contributors/klara-brandst%C3%A4tter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Content Creation Using Record and Replay</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/content-creation-using-record-and-replay/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/content-creation-using-record-and-replay/</guid><description>We presented our paper Dialogues For One: Single-User Content Creation Using Immersive Record and Replay at VRST 2023.
With the help of indicators showing when a recorded avatar would speak or grab an object, a single user could create believable conversations and object interactions with their previously recorded self. Watch the video to see how we created single-user dialogues and object interaction! In the past, we implemented a record and replay tool in Ubiq with which we could easily populate a virtual space with many characters by recording over previous replays.</description></item><item><title>Dialogues For One: Single-User Content Creation Using Immersive Record and Replay</title><link>https://ubiq.online/publication/dialogues-for-one/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/publication/dialogues-for-one/</guid><description>ℹ️ The Unity project and dataset are available here. Cite with BibTex @inproceedings{10.1145/3611659.3615695, author = {Brandst\&amp;#34;{a}tter, Klara and Steed, Anthony}, title = {Dialogues For One: Single-User Content Creation Using Immersive Record and Replay}, year = {2023}, isbn = {9798400703287}, publisher = {Association for Computing Machinery}, address = {New York, NY, USA}, url = {https://doi.org/10.1145/3611659.3615695}, doi = {10.1145/3611659.3615695}, booktitle = {Proceedings of the 29th ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and Technology}, articleno = {9}, numpages = {11}, keywords = {content creation, virtual reality, record and replay}, location = {Christchurch, New Zealand}, series = {VRST &amp;#39;23} }</description></item><item><title>Extending the Open Source Social Virtual Reality Ecosystem to the Browser in Ubiq</title><link>https://ubiq.online/publication/extending-to-the-browser/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/publication/extending-to-the-browser/</guid><description>ℹ️ To get the code, clone the samples-browserextended branch and take a look at the Web3D blog post for more detailed instructions. Cite with BibTex @inproceedings{10.1145/3611314.3615903, author = {Friston, Sebastian and Congdon, Ben and Numan, Nels and Brandst\&amp;#34;{a}tter, Klara and Izzouzi, Lisa and Thiel, Felix and Zhang, Jingyi and Giunchi, Daniele and Swapp, David and Steed, Anthony}, title = {Extending the Open Source Social Virtual Reality Ecosystem to the Browser in Ubiq}, year = {2023}, isbn = {9798400703249}, publisher = {Association for Computing Machinery}, address = {New York, NY, USA}, url = {https://doi.</description></item><item><title>Ubiq-Exp: a Toolkit to Build and Run Remote and Distributed Mixed Reality Experiments</title><link>https://ubiq.online/publication/ubiq-exp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/publication/ubiq-exp/</guid><description>ℹ️ Source code for Ubiq-Exp will be posted to this page soon! Cite with BibTex @article{10.3389/frvir.2022.912078, title={Ubiq-Exp: A Toolkit to Build and Run Remote and Distributed Mixed Reality Experiments}, author={Steed, Anthony and Izzouzi, Lisa and Brandst{\&amp;#34;a}tter, Klara and Friston, Sebastian and Congdon, Benjamin James and Olkkonen, Otto and Giunchi, Daniele and Numan, Nels and Swapp, David}, journal={Frontiers in Virtual Reality}, pages={131}, publisher={Frontiers} }</description></item><item><title>Ubiq Tutorial at ISMAR 2022</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ismar-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ismar-2022/</guid><description>Abstract One of the most promising applications of consumer virtual reality technology is its use for remote collaboration. A very wide variety of social virtual reality (SVR) applications are now available; from competitive games amongst small numbers of players; through to conference-like setups supporting dozens of visitors. Indeed many participants at ISMAR 2022 will be experiencing at least some of the conference through a SVR application. The implementations strategies of different SVR applications are very diverse, with few standards or conventions to follow.</description></item><item><title>Ubiq Tutorial at IEEE VR 2022</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2022/</guid><description>Abstract One of the most promising applications of consumer virtual reality technology is its use for remote collaboration. A very wide variety of social virtual reality (SVR) applications are now available; from competitive games amongst small numbers of players; through to conference-like setups supporting dozens of visitors. Indeed many participants at IEEE Virtual Reality 2022 will be experiencing at least some of the conference through a SVR application. The implementations strategies of different SVR applications are very diverse, with few standards or conventions to follow.</description></item><item><title>Ubiq: A System to Build Flexible Social Virtual Reality Experiences</title><link>https://ubiq.online/publication/ubiq-paper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/publication/ubiq-paper/</guid><description>🏆 This paper won the Cyber Agent Award at VRST 2021! Cite with BibTex @inproceedings{10.1145/3489849.3489871, author = {Friston, Sebastian J and Congdon, Ben J and Swapp, David and Izzouzi, Lisa and Brandst\&amp;#34;{a}tter, Klara and Archer, Daniel and Olkkonen, Otto and Thiel, Felix Johannes and Steed, Anthony}, title = {Ubiq: A System to Build Flexible Social Virtual Reality Experiences}, year = {2021}, isbn = {9781450390927}, publisher = {Association for Computing Machinery}, address = {New York, NY, USA}, url = {https://doi.</description></item><item><title>Merry X-Mas from the Ubiq team!</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/merry-x-mas-from-the-ubiq-team/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/merry-x-mas-from-the-ubiq-team/</guid><description>The video was created with a record and replay feature developed in Ubiq.</description></item><item><title>Cyber Agent Award at VRST 2021</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/cyber-agent-award-at-vrst-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/cyber-agent-award-at-vrst-2021/</guid><description>📄 More information on the publication that received the award can be found here.</description></item></channel></rss>