<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ubiq.online/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building Asymmetric Social VR with the Browser</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/building-asymmetric-social-vr-with-the-browser/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/building-asymmetric-social-vr-with-the-browser/</guid><description>Introduction At Web3D 2023 we presented a paper on one of our recent projects, Extending the Open Source Social Virtual Reality Ecosystem to the Browser in Ubiq.
In this project we set up Ubiq to build a library enabling Ubiq Peers to be written in JavaScript for the browser.
Ubiq has always supported the browser, but this work takes it much further.
To start with, we now have only one JavaScript codebase, and the browser library builds from this using Rollup, ensuring parity between our NodeJs and Browser classes going forward, and making samples for one applicable to the other.</description></item><item><title>Using Ubiq to Enable Independent Setups</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/using-ubiq-to-enable-independent-setups/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/using-ubiq-to-enable-independent-setups/</guid><description>Conferences and industry fairs are fantastic opportunities to show one’s project and do networking of the human kind. The networking of devices, however, is a different story. Conference networks are notoriously overcrowded, and even good infrastructure sometimes struggles with the large number of attendees and their numerous devices. This is a problem for demonstrations that rely on devices being networked together with little latency, such as social VR applications.
This was a problem for our colleagues at the Institute of Cardiovascular Science (ICS) at UCL and the Great Ormond Street Hospital (GOSH) because they were scheduled to host multiple virtual anatomy labs over five days at the World Congress of Paediatric Cardiology and Cardiac Surgery (WCPCCS).</description></item><item><title>Ubiq Tutorial at IEEE VR 2023</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2023/</guid><description>One of the most promising applications of consumer virtual reality technology is its use for remote collaboration. A very wide variety of social virtual reality (SVR) applications are now available from competitive games amongst small numbers of players through to conference-like setups supporting dozens of visitors.
Ubiq is an open source tool that allows developers to very quickly build SVR applications. In this short tutorial, we will introduce some of the capabilities of Ubiq, demonstrate some of the tools it has, and work through a complete example of how to build a non-trivial application including custom distributed behaviours.</description></item><item><title>Ubiq-Genie</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-genie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-genie/</guid><description>-- The integration of external (open-source) projects with social virtual reality (VR) has the potential to enhance the way we collaborate within virtual environments. For example, recent advances in generative AI provide the ability to synthesize textual, auditory, or visual data, enabling new types of virtual experiences. However, these applications often require a high level of processing power, which is typically not available on untethered mixed-reality devices.
Ubiq-Genie addresses this by building on the open-source Ubiq social VR platform and provides a modular approach to server-assisted social VR applications.</description></item><item><title>Serving Secure WebSockets</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/serving-secure-websockets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/serving-secure-websockets/</guid><description>Introduction Ubiq 0.0.3 supports building for WebGL out-of-the-box in Unity.
Ubiq has always supported Javascript clients, but now users have the option of building native browser clients, or building for the web directly in Unity.
WebGL support is experimental, and some features are still a work in progress, such as Voice Chat.
This post is not about building for the browser however, but what it required to support the browser behind the scenes&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Extending the server</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/extending-the-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/extending-the-server/</guid><description>Introduction Ubiq sessions are made up of Peers connected in a Peer Group.
By default, peers join Rooms on the server. Each room is a peer group, and group members exchange all messages with all other members.
This is just one possibility however&amp;hellip;
In this post we show how to extend the server without making upstream code changes, so we can implement different multicasting behaviours, and so build different peer groups, for research and experimentation.</description></item><item><title>Latest API improvements</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/latest-api-improvements/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/latest-api-improvements/</guid><description>Introduction In Ubiq 0.0.3 we have made a number of changes to improve ease of use.
Our main goal was to simplify object addressing and initialisation - to make creating networked objects as quick and easy as possible, and avoid messages ending up where they aren&amp;rsquo;t expected.
Another, separate, goal was the ability to automatically synchronise Components, for those who just want to build networked objects as quickly as possible.</description></item><item><title>Ubiq Tutorial at ISMAR 2022</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ismar-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ismar-2022/</guid><description>Abstract One of the most promising applications of consumer virtual reality technology is its use for remote collaboration. A very wide variety of social virtual reality (SVR) applications are now available; from competitive games amongst small numbers of players; through to conference-like setups supporting dozens of visitors. Indeed many participants at ISMAR 2022 will be experiencing at least some of the conference through a SVR application. The implementations strategies of different SVR applications are very diverse, with few standards or conventions to follow.</description></item><item><title>Ubiq Tutorial at IEEE VR 2022</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2022/</guid><description>Abstract One of the most promising applications of consumer virtual reality technology is its use for remote collaboration. A very wide variety of social virtual reality (SVR) applications are now available; from competitive games amongst small numbers of players; through to conference-like setups supporting dozens of visitors. Indeed many participants at IEEE Virtual Reality 2022 will be experiencing at least some of the conference through a SVR application. The implementations strategies of different SVR applications are very diverse, with few standards or conventions to follow.</description></item><item><title>Merry X-Mas from the Ubiq team!</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/merry-x-mas-from-the-ubiq-team/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/merry-x-mas-from-the-ubiq-team/</guid><description>The video was created with a record and replay feature developed in Ubiq.</description></item></channel></rss>