<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ruijun (Phoenix) Sun on</title><link>https://ubiq.online/contributors/ruijun-phoenix-sun/</link><description>Recent content in Ruijun (Phoenix) Sun on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:19:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ubiq.online/contributors/ruijun-phoenix-sun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ubiq and Ubiq-Genie Tutorial at IEEE VR 2026</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-and-ubiq-genie-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2026/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-and-ubiq-genie-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2026/</guid><description>Full sets of slides and video of the tutorial will be available after IEEE VR 2026. Summary In this tutorial we will explore how to build a wide variety of collaborative extended reality (XR) systems using the Ubiq software and then extend them to support artificial-intelligence (AI) based processes using Ubiq-Genie. Ubiq is an open source platform. It is designed to be easily extensible. It enables development of applications or systems that would be difficult or time-consuming on commercial systems.</description></item><item><title>Ubiq Tutorial at IEEE VR 2025</title><link>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ubiq.online/blog/ubiq-tutorial-at-ieee-vr-2025/</guid><description>Full sets of slides and video of the tutorial will be available after IEEE VR 2025. Summary In this tutorial we will explore how to build a wide variety of collaborative extended reality (XR) systems using the Ubiq software. Ubiq is an open source platform. It is designed to be easily extensible. It enables development of applications or systems that would be difficult or time-consuming on commercial systems. The tutorial will start with basic concepts, but then explore how more complete demonstrations can be built using new features that have been built on Ubiq in the past couple of years.</description></item></channel></rss>